- I have taken the given tableau dashboard as the reference  point to to my analysis. It helped me set the direction of the analysis. However I felt it was missing few more worksheets to find the  cause of the problem.

Approach followed by me -
Step 1:Q) Potential Shipping companies causing shipment delays ?
A) In the Delay by shipper worksheet, we found out 
Federal Amulgated, Xpressway and Cross Country express Shippers are top 3 shipping companies causing high shipment delays.


— Renaming ( Federal Amulgated, Xpressway and Cross Country express as Rabble-Rouser).——

Step2:Q) What factors are causing these shippers delay? Is the product not available to ship on time  or the long distance an issue for delayed shipments?
A) On further analysis I found out that the Shipment delay is similar to ( Actual Ship Date - Expected ship date) and  distance can be ruled out as the potential factor for shipment delays.


Further Exploratory Analysis ——

Step3:Q) Lets look at the Shipper Delay Over time?
A) In the corresponding worksheet, we observe an unusual increase of shipment delay(Hrs) in the month of June by the rabble-rousers.

Step4) Why is the Shipping Delay hiked in the month of June for rabble-rousers? Is it t do with the seasonal pattern or other economical issues? Or could be something related with the customers?
A)In the Shipment Delay in June worksheet, We observe that the rabble-rouser’s unexpected shipment delay is explained by two customers.
The Spirit Soda and Accenton. 


Step5) Does Spirit Soda and Accenton contribute to major profit share in our company?
A) In the worksheet Profit by customer we observe that Spirit Soda sums up t $208,152 profit. Which clearly contributes to major chunk of the profits.

Further Analysis ————

Step6) Did high shipment delays actually affect the sales and profits?
A) In the Sales by Spirit Soda, we observe that the following month of high shipment delays ( June) we see fall in sales and profit.


This Analysis can be helpful in finding out one of the major causes in high shipment delays, narrowing down to a particular customer.


